<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">

<channel>
  <title>James O'Hara's Next Year, D.C.</title>
  <link>https://nextyeardc.com</link>
  <ns0:link href="https://nextyeardc.com/nextyeardc_rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <description>A DC sports blog</description>
  <item><title>Do Not Trade MacKenzie Gore</title><link>https://nextyeardc.com/post/DoNotTradeMacKenzieGore.html</link><description>The idea of a Gore trade seems to be more of a product of bored writers looking for patterns based off of three observations. First, that the Nationals are bad this season. Second, that Gore has the same amount of time until free agency as Juan Soto had when the Nats traded him. And third, that Gore has Scott Boras for an agent. Bingo bango, you have a situation that demands a trade.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 12:03:26 EDT</pubDate></item><item>
    <title>Expectations for the Mystics Second Half</title>
    <link>https://nextyeardc.com/post/ExpectationsfortheMysticsSecondHalf.html</link>
    <description>The Washington Mystics, in a season that looked destined to be historically terrible, are holding onto the final playoff spot at 11-12, with just 2.5 games separating them from 4th place. As we enter the second half of the season how much should we be adjusting our expectations?</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Checking In on the 2026 Nats Pitchers</title>
    <link>https://nextyeardc.com/post/Checkinginonthe2026NatsPitchers.html</link>
    <description>Last Friday I did a run down of the young Nationals on the offensive side of the ball, breaking things down by their 2026 status based on their results so far. Now it’s the pitchers’ turn.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Checking In on the 2026 Nats</title>
    <link>https://nextyeardc.com/post/CheckingInonthe2026Nats.html</link>
    <description>With the second half of the season about to get underway I thought it was a good time to check in on how the young Nationals are doing and where they might fit in on the 2026 Nationals and beyond. </description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>The Rizzoless Draft</title>
    <link>https://nextyeardc.com/post/TheRizzolessDraft.html</link>
    <description>The Washington Nationals just had their first draft without Mike Rizzo’s involvement since 2006 which had everyone looking for clues about the direction of the front office. </description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Fire Davey Martinez</title>
    <link>https://nextyeardc.com/post/FireDaveyMartinez.html</link>
    <description>I've mentioned it on Twitter before that Davey Martinez has gotten a lot of undeserved cover from the popular memory of the Nats rebuild. This is his eighth season as manager and almost assuredly his sixth with a losing record.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>A Spin Through the Rotation</title>
    <link>https://nextyeardc.com/post/ASpinThroughtheRotation.html</link>
    <description>If you are like me, you also have probably found that when it comes to the Nats’ starting rotation there are some narratives in your head due to which games you happened to have caught, that are not entirely based in reality. So I decided to dive into the numbers to catch up on what’s really going on with the Nats starters.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 6 Jun 2025 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>What's Next for CJ Abrams</title>
    <link>https://nextyeardc.com/post/What'sNextforCJAbrams.html</link>
    <description>If you’ve watched any Nats game this year you’ve probably noticed CJ Abrams. We’re 50 games into the season and he has 8 home runs, 9 steals, is batting .311 with a 160 wRC+.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Optimism for a Struggling Core</title>
    <link>https://nextyeardc.com/post/OptimismforaStrugglingCore.html</link>
    <description>Just yesterday Baseball Prospectus announced new additions of their plate discipline metric SEAGER and their batted ball metrics including 90th percentile exit velocity were added to their leaderboards and player cards. To celebrate let’s take a look at two young players that are supposed to be establishing the Nats’ new core and instead find themselves mired in mediocrity: Dylan Crews and Luis García Jr.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Clowns in the Bullpen</title>
    <link>https://nextyeardc.com/post/ClownsintheBullpen.html</link>
    <description>I admit this one got away from me. I started doing the research for this post last week in anticipation of posting it last Friday and then I dug deeper and dug deeper and next thing I know it’s another week later and I finally have a post. Luckily (?) the Nationals bullpen did not take advantage of my delay by suddenly being good.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Should We Be Concerned About Dylan Crews</title>
    <link>https://nextyeardc.com/post/ShouldWeBeConcernedAboutDylanCrews.html</link>
    <description>I had started working on this post to hopefully find some small positives around Dylan Crews’ 0-18 with 10 strikeouts start to the season and instead what I found was a fractal of bad news.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 4 Apr 2025 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>The Nats Played a Game Let's Overreact</title>
    <link>https://nextyeardc.com/post/TheNatsPlayedAGameLet'sOverreact.html</link>
    <description>With Mark Lerner still failing to scam Mayor Bowser into building a dome over Nats Park, the Nationals are taking their traditional day off after Opening Day which gives us plenty of time to let our imaginations run wild after one game. Here are four big thoughts after game 1 of 162.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Analyzing My Bracket Hunches</title>
    <link>https://nextyeardc.com/post/AnalyzingMyBracketHunches.html</link>
    <description>As we are in the grips of March Madness and filling out brackets I figured it would be a fun time to breakdown the “rules”, in some cases more like advanced hunches, I’ve developed over the last 20 years of making picks and see if they’re actually useful or actively harmful. </description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Ovechkin's Leadership Should Be Recognized More</title>
    <link>https://nextyeardc.com/post/Ovechkin'sLeadershipShouldBeRecognizedMore.html</link>
    <description>As Alexander Ovechkin closes in on the all-time goal scoring record a common refrain is that while he is undoubtedly the greatest goal scorer of all time, that’s pretty much all he is bringing to the table. Of course, that’s been a fairly common criticism ever since he donned a Washington Capitals uniform.</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Are The Nats Supposed to Be Good?</title>
    <link>https://nextyeardc.com/post/AreTheNatsSupposedtoBeGood.html</link>
    <description>I know the easy thing to do is say no and click away, but I implore you not to, because I am not asking the question from the perspective of cold hard facts.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
  </item>
</channel>

</rss>